It takes a lot of guts and a helluva sense of
humor to live life in Arnold's shoes.
Torch Song Trilogy is a comedy, drama, romance film directed by Paul Bogart.
Arnold Beckoff is looking for love and acceptance, but as a gay man working as a
female impersonator in 1970s New York City, neither come easily.
After a series of heartaches, Arnold believes he has found the love of
his life in Alan, and the couple make plans to adopt.
But when tragedy strikes, Arnold's life is shaken to its very core, leading to a confrontation
with his overbearing mother, who has never approved of her son's lifestyle.
Arnold Beckoff, played by Harvey Fierstein.
Alan Simon, played by Matthew Broderick.
Ma Beckoff, played by Anne Bancroft.
Ed Reese, played by Brian Kerwin.
David, played by Eddie Castrodad.
Phil Beckoff, played by Lorry Goldman.
Torch Song Trilogy is a 1988 American comedy drama film adapted by
Harvey Fierstein from his play of the same name.
The film was directed by Paul Bogart and stars Fierstein as Arnold, Anne Bancroft as Ma
Beckoff, Matthew Broderick as Alan, Brian Kerwin as Ed, and Eddie Castrodad as David.
Executive Producer Ronald K.
Fierstein is Harvey Fierstein's brother.
Scott Salmon choreographed the musical sequences in the film.
Fierstein created the role of Bertha Venation to highlight the
work of female impersonator Charles Pierce.
Broderick originally refused the role of Alan because he was
recuperating from an automobile accident in Northern Ireland.
Tate Donovan was cast, but two days into the rehearsal period Broderick had a
change of heart and contacted Fierstein, who fired Donovan.
Although the play was over four hours, the film was restricted to a running time of two hours
at the insistence of New Line Cinema, necessitating much editing and excisions.
The time period the film covers is several years earlier
than the time period of the original play.
The film explores themes of new york city, homophobia, drag
queen, based on play or musical, male homosexuality.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.